Guilt is a place you can never leave.
Return to Silent Hill is a horror, mystery film directed by Christophe Gans.
When James receives a mysterious letter from his lost love Mary, he is drawn
to Silent Hill—a once-familiar town now consumed by darkness.
As he searches for her, James faces monstrous creatures and unravels a
terrifying truth that will push him to the edge of his sanity.
James Sunderland, played by Jeremy Irvine.
Mary Crane  / Angela / Maria / Moth Mary, played by Hannah Emily Anderson.
Armless, played by Ljiljana Velimirov.
Armless / Spider Lady, played by Giulia Pelagatti.
Laura, played by Evie Templeton.
Pyramid Head, played by Robert Strange.
Return to Silent Hill is a 2026 supernatural psychological horror film written and directed by Christophe Gans,
co-written by Sandra Vo-Anh and Will Schneider, and produced by Victor Hadida through his Davis Films banner.
Loosely based on the 2001 video game Silent Hill 2 by Konami, the film serves as the
third installment in the Silent Hill film series and a reboot in the series.
Starring Jeremy Irvine and Hannah Emily Anderson, it follows James Sunderland, a broken man who
receives a mysterious letter which calls him back to Silent Hill in search of his lost love.
However, he finds a once-recognizable town and encounters terrifying figures
both familiar and new, and begins to question his own sanity.
Plans for a new Silent Hill film adaptation initially began in December 2006, with Gans and former writer Roger
Avary had been hired to helm a film adaptation of Silent Hill 2, which was greenlit by Sony.
This project did not move forward and was instead released as a sequel titled
Silent Hill: Revelation (2012) without Gans and Avary's involvement.
By 2020, Gans announced he was working on a new Silent Hill
film, adapting the events of the second game.
The film was officially green-lit in October 2022, with Gans
returning to write and direct the project.
An international co-production between France and the United States, the film
was shot in Germany and Serbia from April 2023 to February 2024.
Return to Silent Hill was released theatrically in the United States by Cineverse and Iconic Events Releasing on
January 23, 2026, and it will be released in France by Metropolitan Filmexport on February 4, 2026.
The film received negative reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of monster, supernatural, letter, painter, sequel.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.